Guide to the Clifford I. Nass papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Clifford I. Nass papers
1977-2010
SC1192
Nass, Clifford Ivar
4.5 Linear feet (3 cartons)
The papers include Nass' teaching files, research files, and publications related to the social-psychological aspects of human-interactive media interaction, chronic media multitasking, and automotive interfaces.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
This collection given Stanford University, Special Collections in February 2014.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Separated Materials
The BIG idea: Festival for Automotive Interfaces (CHIMe Lab), CARS, Media at Stanford University, REVS Program at Stanford, 2013, poster. Added to the Stanford University Poster Collection, SC1030.
Biographical/Historical note
Clifford Ivar Nass, was born in 1958 in New Jersey. He earned a BA in Mathematics from Princeton University in 1981; and his M.A. and Ph.D. in Sociology from Princeton in 1986. That same year Nass joined the faculty at Stanford University as a professor of Communications. At the time of his death, Nass was the Thomas M. Storke Professor and had courtesy appointments in Computer Science, Education, Law, and Sociology. Nass was also affiliated with the programs in Science, Technology, and Society and Symbolic Systems (cognitive science).
Nass was the co-creator of The Media Equation theory, and a renowned authority on human-computer interaction. He was also known for his work on individual differences associated with multitasking.
Nass was the director of the Communication between Humans and Interactive Media (CHIMe) Lab, co-director of Kozmetsky Global Collaboratory (KGC) and its Real-time Venture Design Laboratory (ReVeL), a co-founder of TeachAIDS, the co-Director of the CARS (Center for Automotive Research at Stanford) Program, and the Director of the Revs Program at Stanford University.
Nass died in 2013 of a heart attack while hiking.
Text excerpted from: http://www.stanford.edu/~nass/ http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clifford_Nass
Scope and Contents
The papers include Nass' teaching files, research files, and publications related to the social-psychological aspects of human-interactive media interaction, chronic media multitasking, and automotive interfaces. Also included are materials related to Nass' tenure as a Resident Fellow at the Stanford University Otero House dorm.
Access Terms
Kozmetsky Global Collaboratory and the Center for Automotive Research at Stanford University (CARS)..; Stanford University. Communication between Humans and Interactive Media (CHIMe) Lab..; Stanford University. Computer Science Department. Faculty.; Stanford University. Department of Communications. Faculty.; The Revs Program at Stanford.; Computer multitasking; Human-computer interaction; Stanford University--Student housing.
Collection Contents
- Teaching files
  - Course reader: Theories of Communication, Technology, and Society (Part A). Communication 371, TVTSS 271, Sociology 371., 1988-1989 Winter (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Course reader: Digital Media in Society, 2009 Spring (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Course reader: Always Connected. Communication 169/269 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Course reader: Theory of Communication. Communication 311., 1999 Fall (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Course reader: Computers and Interfaces. Communications 169/269, 2006 Winter (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Course reader: Theory of Communication (Part IV), 1988 Autumn (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Otero House-Resident Fellow Information, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Otero House yearbook, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Otero House yearbook, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Notes: Soc 504/PR509 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Publications
  - REVS it Upp: Robot-Enhanced Vehicles: Safety, Information, Training, and User and Passenger Pleasure. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Wired for Speech: How Voice Activates and Advances the Human-Computer Relationship., 2005 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Media Equation: How People Treat Computers, Televisions, and New Media as Real People and Places., 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Office Assistant Introduction: Briefing on Social Interface Research., 1996 Jun 27 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - PASCGRAF and the Haloed Line Effect. BA Thesis, Princeton University., 1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Society as Computer: The Structure and Skill of Information Work in the United States, 1900-1980. Dissertation, Princeton University., 1986 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - The Man Who Lied to His Laptop: What Machines Teach Us about Human Relationships. Clifford Nass with Corina Yen. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - The Man Who Lied to His Laptop: What Machines Teach Us about Human Relationships. Clifford Nass with Corina Yen. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - A Dielectric Theory of Gravity. Michael Jay Nass. BA Thesis, Princeton University., 1977 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Research files
  - HRI 2006: Proceedings of the 2006 ACM Conference on Human-Robot Interaction, 2006 Mar 2-4 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The REVS Institute: 6th Biennial Symposium on Connoisseurship and the Collectible Car, 2010 Mar 7-10 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - AVIOS Speech Develepor's Conference & Expo, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bob 2.0, 1995 Jun 19 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cinemania and Rockmania Projects: The Character Evaluation Study, 1995 May 5 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - iTV Project: The Platform/Interface Study, 1995 Nov 30 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - CAMP Stanford Projects, 2001 Oct 10 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Folk Revel: A Report on the Hyderabad Workshop, 2007 Mar 26-31 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - International Workshop on "Ubiquitous Media and Social Infrastructure.", 2005 Aug 26 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Extended Abstracts: Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, 2001 Mar 31-Apr 5 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Fourth IEEE International Conference on Multimodal Interfaces, 2002 Oct 14-16 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Dare to Dream: Children's Responses to a Computer Game with and without REX Toys, 1997 Feb 9 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - CHI '94: Celebrating Interdependence-Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, 1994 Apr 24-28 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - CHI '96: Common Ground: Conference Companion, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Kozmetsky Global Collaboratory, 2003-2010 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Exhibits to the Videotaped Deposition of Clifford I. Nass, Ph.D., Volume 1 (Part 1), 2004 May 3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Exhibits to the Videotaped Deposition of Clifford I. Nass, Ph.D., Volume 1 (Part 2), 2004 May 3 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Videotaped Deposition of Clifford I. Nass, Ph.D., Volume 1 (Index), 2004 May 3 (Box 3, Folder 3)